<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Konstantin Nazarov</title>
    <link>https://knazarov.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Konstantin Nazarov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Konstantin Nazarov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://knazarov.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On keeping notes</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/on_keeping_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/on_keeping_notes/</guid>
      <description>I often struggle to keep good notes. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve read and watched a lot of stuff that could be useful to other people, and that really deserves to be written about. Problem is, even if I have it buried somewhere around my TODO lists or bookmarks, retrieving something useful on a specific topic is nearly impossible.
For instance, I remember that The School of Life or Tim Urban&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Wait, but why?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully vendored Emacs configuration</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/fully_vendored_emacs_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/fully_vendored_emacs_configuration/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve rewritten my emacs configuration many times. Initially I started with a plain .emacs configuration file and copy-pasted stuff from blogs or wikis that I liked. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t synchronized between my home and work machines. It was also before GitHub came to life, and long before storing your dotfiles there became fashionable.
Then I stumbled upon Prelude and Spacemacs, both of which provide featureful &amp;ldquo;batteries included&amp;rdquo; configurations that are highly advanced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting goals and figuring out values</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/setting_goals_and_figuring_out_values_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/setting_goals_and_figuring_out_values_2020/</guid>
      <description>I have a very long history with struggling to set goals that resonate with my true motives. This post is a summary of what I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with. It may be of some use to you, but please take everything here with a grain of salt, as everyone is unique and there are no universal ways that would work for everyone.
There is a post at LessWrong called Beware of other-optimizing that pretty much sums up my experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we celebrate birthdays at Tarantool</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/how_we_celebrate_birthdays_at_tarantool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/how_we_celebrate_birthdays_at_tarantool/</guid>
      <description>When I joined Tarantool, there were only about 10 people in the whole team. We used to fit in one room on daily standups.
One day I decided to do something for the people I work with, and asked if they are fine with me organizing birthday parties. The deal was that everyone who has a birthday buys pizza and other folks collectively buy them a present.
I had a simple python script that created a Telegram chat and invited everyone except the person having a birthday, where we had a discussion about the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I designed an application framework for a database</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/why_i_designed_app_framework_for_a_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/why_i_designed_app_framework_for_a_database/</guid>
      <description>Tarantool is an in-memory database, that happens to have a general purpose programming language onboard. While some databases like MySQL or Postgres allow you to write stored procedures, they are nowhere near as powerful as, say, Python. And even if they have support for external languages, they always feel like second-class citizens because usually they were bolted on after these products have matured. In tarantool, Lua has been added very early, and now covers the entirety of the database API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I keep a plaintext journal</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/how_i_keep_a_plaintext_journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/how_i_keep_a_plaintext_journal/</guid>
      <description>Keeping a journal has become a transformative experience for me. I tried to start writing out my thoughts multiple times last 5 years or so. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t click until my last attempt.
What helped me in the end was to concentrate on analyzing problems that really bother me and be curious and frank about it. I won&amp;rsquo;t tell you there was any particular tool or magical method that helped me to jumpstart it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up postfix in OS X 10.14 (Mojave)</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/setting_up_postfix_on_os_x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/setting_up_postfix_on_os_x/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this post because there are lots of articles that describe how to set up postfix on OS X which recommend strange things, like disabling System Integrity Protection. I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how it can be achieved easily without any ugly hacks.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why you may want to use postfix on OS X:
 if you are managing an OS X server (like in a build farm) and want to be able to send automated emails if you use mutt or other mailer like mu4e and want a persistent outgoing mail queue that works offline to write and debug scripts that use default system mailer  First thing you need to know about postfix in OS X is that it is already set up and running!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Herokuish apps in Docker</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/herokuish_apps_in_docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/herokuish_apps_in_docker/</guid>
      <description>Heroku allows you to build an app, push the code to a git repository and have it automatically deployed to a server. The beauty of this solution is that if you follow certain simple conventions, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to invest any brainpower into the deployment at all.
Then comes Dokku, which is built on the same principles as Heroku and can serve as a drop-in replacement for it on your own server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposing Docker containers to external network</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/posts/exposing_docker_containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/posts/exposing_docker_containers/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever tried to assign a routable and externally visible IP address to your Docker containers, you probably know that it&amp;rsquo;s not a trivial task. There are a few posts out there that show a few interesting methods, like this or this or even from the creators of Docker itself.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been digging for a better method, that will still allow you to use Docker API and don&amp;rsquo;t execute any host-side commands after starting every container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
My name is Konstantin. I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineering professional with 10 years of experience. During my career I worked with a diverse set of technologies, ranging from RTOS kernel development to highly loaded web services.
Currently I work at Tarantool where I manage a team building enterprise solutions based off our own database and application server.
I offer consulting in application architecture and implementing MVPs.
For individuals I offer productivity and goal setting coaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/pages/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/pages/contact/</guid>
      <description>The best and most reliable way to contact me is by email: mail@knazarov.com. I read and answer everything. If you find that I didn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; it is most likely due to your message ending up in my Spam folder. Try sending it again with different subject and/or from different email address.
If you would like to chat with me &amp;ndash; write to this telegram account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/pages/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/pages/projects/</guid>
      <description>Simple Applicant Tracking System http://hiring.knazarov.com is a simple Applicant Tracking System that helps make hiring in small teams easier. It has just a bare minimum of functionality: a table with all your candidates, ability to upload CVs and comment on individual candidates. It also allows a team of people to join together into an organization and collaborate on the shared pool of candidaets.
I&amp;rsquo;ve developed it mostly for my own purposes while working at Tarantool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>