<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Konstantin Nazarov</title>
    <link>https://knazarov.com/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Konstantin Nazarov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Konstantin Nazarov</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://knazarov.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
My name is Konstantin. I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineering professional with 10 years of experience. During my career I worked with a diverse set of technologies, ranging from RTOS kernel development to highly loaded web services.
Currently I work at Tarantool where I manage a team building enterprise solutions based off our own database and application server.
I offer consulting in application architecture and implementing MVPs.
For individuals I offer productivity and goal setting coaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/pages/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/pages/contact/</guid>
      <description>The best and most reliable way to contact me is by email: mail@knazarov.com. I read and answer everything. If you find that I didn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; it is most likely due to your message ending up in my Spam folder. Try sending it again with different subject and/or from different email address.
If you would like to chat with me &amp;ndash; write to this telegram account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://knazarov.com/pages/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knazarov.com/pages/projects/</guid>
      <description>Simple Applicant Tracking System http://hiring.knazarov.com is a simple Applicant Tracking System that helps make hiring in small teams easier. It has just a bare minimum of functionality: a table with all your candidates, ability to upload CVs and comment on individual candidates. It also allows a team of people to join together into an organization and collaborate on the shared pool of candidaets.
I&amp;rsquo;ve developed it mostly for my own purposes while working at Tarantool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>